jobzella.com 2015-03-15

# privacy | Jobzella.com

Date of Last Revision: Nov 4, 2013

Being part of Jobzella means sharing information about yourself with other professionals, communicating with them, as well as working privately on your own. By default, your account is set up to share the information that we have found the vast majority of our Users are interested in sharing. But the amount and type of information you decide to share, and with whom you share it, is up to you.

Here are the three main types of information on Jobzella:

Information about yourself that you share. This is the information that your connections, other professionals, and companies see about you. This includes your profile and your contributions to discussions on Jobzella Groups, Answers, or other community features Jobzella may offer such as “Profile Stats” which, if you choose to opt-in, can show you who viewed your profile (and will show others when you visited their profiles). You have control over what you share, and you can update information at any time.

Communication. We help you communicate with connections and other professionals. Some of this is one-to-one, some of it is in groups, and some of it is public discussion. You decide how much or how little you wish to communicate to individuals or groups.

Private activity. We also provide tools that you can use privately on Jobzella (for example, searching, or adding notes to your connections information.) These actions and information are private and we don't share or distribute them to others on the website.

Of course, maintaining your trust is our top concern, so we adhere to the following principles to protect your privacy:

  * We do not rent, sell, or otherwise provide your personally identifiable information to third parties without your consent, except as described in this policy or as required by law.
  * We do not share any information you have not chosen to display on your Jobzella profile to other parties, unless compelled by law, or as necessary to enforce our User Agreement or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Jobzella, its Users, and the public.
  * All information that you provide will be protected with industry standard protocols and technology.

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by means of a notice on our home page so that you may access and review the changes to this document in advance of your continued use of the service. If you object to any changes, you may deactivate your account. By continuing to use the Jobzella service after notice of changes has been sent to you or published on the Jobzella website, you are consenting to the changes.

####  What Jobzella’s Privacy Policy Covers: 

We collect your personal information in the following ways:

A. Registration:

In order to become a User, you must provide us the following information to create an account: name, email address, country, and password. Without this minimal amount of information, you cannot create a Jobzella account. Like other passwords, you should choose one that is known only by you. Jobzella requests other information from you during the registration process, (e.g., gender, location, etc.) that Jobzella uses to provide better, more customized services such as language-specific profile pages and updates, better ads, and more valuable career opportunities. You acknowledge that this information is personal to you, and by creating an account on Jobzella, you allow others, including Jobzella, to identify you and to allow Jobzella to use your information.

B. Profile Information:

Once you become a User, you may provide additional information to your Jobzella Profile describing your skills, professional experiences, educational background, recommendations from other Jobzella Users, group memberships, and networking objectives (among other options). Providing additional information about yourself beyond what is minimally required at registration is entirely up to you, but providing additional information enables you to derive more benefit from Jobzella and your professional network by helping you build your professional identity and leverage your professional network and facilitating your search for professional resources, information, and new opportunities. Any information you provide at registration or in the Profile section may be used by Jobzella as described in the Terms of Use Agreement and this Privacy Policy, including for the purpose of allowing professional opportunities to find you on Jobzella, or for serving more relevant advertisements on Jobzella.

C. Contacts Information:

You may choose to manually enter or upload data about your contacts to the “Contacts” section of your account on Jobzella. Information entered into Contacts is only viewable by you. By providing email addresses or other information of non-Users to Jobzella, you represent that you have authority to do so. All information that you enter or upload about your contacts is covered by the Terms of Use Agreement and this Privacy Policy and will enable us to provide customized services such as suggesting people to connect with on Jobzella. NOTE THAT JOBZELLA WILL GRANT ACCESS TO YOUR CONTACT DETIALS ONLY TO RECRUITERS AND CAREER SERVICE PROVIDERS ON JOBZELLA WHO ARE WILLING TO OFFER YOU A CAREER OPPORTUNITY.

D. Customer Service:

We collect information when you interact with Jobzella’s Customer Service in order to accurately categorize and respond to customer inquiries and investigate breaches of our terms.

E. Using the Jobzella Site and Applications:

We receive information when you interact with and use the Jobzella website, Jobzella Applications

F. Cookies:

Like most websites, we use cookies and web log files to track site usage and trends, to improve the quality of our service, to customize your experience on Jobzella, as well as to deliver Jobzella and third-party advertising to Users both on and off the Jobzella site. A cookie is a tiny data file that resides on your computer, mobile phone, or other device, and allows us to recognize you as a User when you return to the Jobzella website using the same computer and web browser. You can remove or block cookies using the settings in your browser, but in some cases doing so may impact your ability to use Jobzella. One type of cookie, known as a “persistent” cookie, is set once you’ve logged in to your Jobzella account. The next time you visit the Jobzella website, the persistent cookie will allow us to recognize you as an existing User so you will not need to log in before using the Services. In order to access or change any of your private information (like a credit card number) or to send a message to another User, however, you must log in securely again with your password even if your computer contains your persistent cookie. Another type of cookie, called a “session” cookie, is used to identify a particular visit to the Jobzella website. Session cookies expire after a short time or when you close your web browser. Other technology like Macromedia’s flash can be used to place the functional equivalent of a cookie on your computer. You can control flash “local stored objects” or “flash cookies” using the Macromedia Website Privacy Settings Panel at www.macromedia.com. Jobzella may use cookie-equivalent technology for the limited purpose of enhancing the security of Jobzella's services. We do not use flash cookies for advertising purposes.

In the course of serving advertisements or optimizing the Services to our Users, we may allow authorized third parties to place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser. Any information provided to third parties through cookies will not be personally identifiable but may provide general segment information (e.g., your industry or geography, career field, or information about your professional or educational background) for the enhancement of your user experience by providing more relevant advertising. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies, but you can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. Jobzella does not store unencrypted personally identifiable information in the cookies.

G. Advertising and Web Beacons:

To support the Services we provide at no cost to our Users, as well as provide a more relevant and useful experience for our Users, we target and serve our own ads and third-party ads both on and off the site using ad networks. Ad networks include third party ad servers, ad agencies, ad exchanges, ad technology vendors and research firms.

We target ads to Users based on general profile categories (e.g., “Sales Manager in Dubai”) or on non-personally identifiable information inferred from a User’s profile (e.g., industry, current or former company, school, compensation bracket, gender, age, ethnic origin, nationality, or other aspects of your life) in addition to a User’s use of Jobzella or their clicking on Jobzella ad inventory. Jobzella does not provide personally identifiable information to any third party ad network.

We use ad technology such as web beacons, pixels, anonymous ad network tags, and cookies to more effectively serve ads to our Users on and off Jobzella through ad networks, as well as to collect anonymized, aggregated auditing, research and reporting for advertisers. Because your web browser requests advertisements and web beacons directly from ad network servers, these networks can view, edit or set their own cookies, just as if you had requested a web page from their site.

H. Log files, IP Addresses and information about your computer and mobile device:

Due to the communications standards on the internet, when you visit the Jobzella website we automatically receive the URL of the site from which you came and the site to which you are going when you leave Jobzella. Additionally, advertisers receive the URL of the page you were on when you click on an ad on Jobzella. Jobzella also receives the internet protocol (“IP”) address of your computer (or the proxy server you use to access the World Wide Web), your computer operating system and type of web browser you are using, email patterns, your mobile device (including your UDID) and mobile operating system (if you are accessing Jobzella using a mobile device), as well as the name of your ISP or your mobile carrier. Jobzella may also receive location data passed to it from third-party services or GPS-enabled devices that you have enabled.

I. Rights to Access, Correct and Eliminate Information About You:

You have a right to access, modify, correct and eliminate the data you supplied to Jobzella. If you update any of your information, we may keep a copy of the information that you originally provided to us in our archives for uses documented in this policy. You may request deletion of your information at any time by contacting our customer service. We will respond to your request within 30 days. Please note, however that information you have shared with others, or that other Users have copied, may also remain visible even if you request its deletion.

J. Data Retention:

Jobzella will retain your information for so long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services, except in the case of our professional plugin impression data, which we de-identify after 12 months. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce this Agreement.

####  Uses of personal information 

We collect your personal information in the following ways:

A. Consent to Jobzella Processing Information About You:

The information you provide to Jobzella may reveal, or allow others to identify, your nationality, ethnic origin, gender, age, and other aspects of your life. By providing information to us for the purposes of creating your User account or adding any additional details to your Jobzella profile, you are expressly and voluntarily accepting the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy and Jobzella’s Terms of Use Agreement that allow Jobzella to process information about you. Supplying information to Jobzella, including any information deemed “sensitive” by applicable law, is entirely voluntary on your part. You have the right to withdraw your consent to Jobzella’s collection and processing of your information at any time, in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy and the User Agreement, by changing your settings or by deactivating your account. Please note that your withdrawal of consent will not be retroactive.

B. Jobzella Communications:

As described in the User Agreement, we will communicate with you through email, notices posted on the Jobzella website, messages to your Jobzella inbox, or through other means available through the service, including mobile text messages. We may send you a series of emails that help inform new Users about the features of the Services, and we will also send you service messages relating to the functioning of the Services. We may also send you messages with promotional information directly or on behalf of our partners, unless you have opted out of receiving promotional information.

You can change your e-mail and contact preferences at any time by logging into your account and changing your setting related to your email notification choices. If you wish, you can also opt-out of receiving promotional emails by sending a request to Jobzella customer service through our customer service.

Please be aware that you cannot opt-out of receiving service messages from Jobzella. Also, if we send communications to you via the carrier service with which you have a mobile communications subscription or otherwise have access, you understand you will pay any service fees associated with your receipt of messages on your mobile device (including text messaging charges).

C. User Communications:

Many communications you initiate through Jobzella will list your primary email address and name in the header of the message. Messages you initiate may also provide aggregate information about your network (for instance how many people are in your network), but will not list the people to whom you’re directly connected. Other communications that you initiate through the Jobzella website, like a request for an introduction, will list your name as the initiator but will not include your personal email address contact information. Your contact information will only be shared with another User if both of you have indicated that you would like to establish contact with each other (follow each other).

D. Customized Content:

We use information you provide to us (or to third parties with whom Jobzella offers combined services) to customize your experience on our website. For example, when you login to your account, we will display the names of new Users who have recently joined your network or recent status updates from your connections.

E. Sharing Information with Third Parties:

Jobzella takes the privacy of our Users very seriously, and we do not sell, rent, or otherwise provide your personally identifiable information to third parties, except as described in this policy. We will also not share other personal information not published to your profile or generated through engagement with other Jobzella services (Groups, Answers, Company Pages, etc.) without your explicit consent or to carry out your instructions (for example, to process payment information) unless, disclosure is reasonably necessary in our opinion to: (1) comply with legal process, including, but not limited to, civil and criminal subpoenas, court orders or other compulsory disclosures; (2) enforce this Agreement; (3) respond to claims of a violation of the rights of third parties, whether or not the third party is a User, individual, or government agency; (4) respond to customer service inquiries; or (5) protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Jobzella, our Users or the public.

Jobzella offers a “public profile” feature that allows Users to publish portions of their Jobzella profile to the public internet. This public profile will be crawled by and displayed through search engines when someone searches for your name. Content distributed through Jobzella’s sharing features and third party integrations may result in displaying some of your information outside of Jobzella. For example, when you post content to a Jobzella Group that is open for public discussion, your content, including your name as the contributor, may be displayed in search engine results. 

We may provide aggregated anonymous data about the usage of the Services to third parties for purposes that we deem, in our sole discretion, to be appropriate, including to prospective advertisers on Jobzella.

F. Polls and Surveys:

Polls and Surveys may be conducted by Jobzella, Jobzella Users or third parties. As a User, you may be invited to participate in polls and surveys from the Jobzella website. Your selection may be random, or it may be based on your non-personally identifiable information, such as job title, geography, company size and/or industry. Whether or not you decide to participate in a poll or survey is completely up to you.

After you complete a poll, you will be given access to the aggregate responses of the poll on a results page. Some third parties may target advertisements to you on the results page based on your answers in the poll.

We may use third parties to deliver incentives to you to participate in surveys or polls. If the delivery of incentives requires your contact information, you may be asked to provide personally identifiable information to the third party fulfilling the incentive offer, which will only be used for the purpose of delivering incentives and/or verifying your contact information. It is up to you whether you provide this information, or whether you desire to take advantage of an incentive.

We will not disclose any personally identifiable information to any third parties in connection with the conduct of any polls or surveys. Your consent to use any personally identifiable information for the purposes set forth in the poll or survey will be explicitly requested by the party conducting it.

G. Search:

We offer search services to help find information and learn more about other Users (for example, you can search for Users with particular expertise or consulting experience, or that you may know from your industry or profession), as well as employment opportunities. Jobzella search also allows Users to find jobs, companies, and contributions to the community aspects of the Jobzella Services, such as Groups and Answers that will help Users more effectively use Jobzella and expand their network. We use information from User profiles, Company Pages, and Answers to inform and refine our search service. And we allow recruiters and service providers only on Jobzella to access your contact details if they want to approach you for a career opportunity.

H. Advertising and Endorsements on Jobzella:

In order to deliver relevant and valuable ads to you and your network, Jobzella may use your name and profile photo in connection with social advertising based on content shared on Jobzella. This advertising may include the fact that you have recommended or endorsed a product or service on Jobzella, followed a company, joined Groups or conversations, established or added content to your profile, etc., and will only be displayed to your Jobzella network

I. Compliance with Legal Process:

It is possible that we may need to disclose personal information, profile information and/or information about your activities as a Jobzella User when required by subpoena or other legal process, or if Jobzella has a good faith belief that disclosure is necessary to (a) investigate, prevent or take action regarding suspected or actual illegal activities or to assist government enforcement agencies; (b) to enforce the User Agreement, to investigate and defend ourselves against any third party claims or allegations, or to protect the security or integrity of our site; and/or (c) to exercise or protect the rights, property or personal safety of Jobzella, our Users, employees, or others.

J. Disclosures to Others as the Result of a Change in Control or Sale of Jobzella:

We may also disclose your personal information and other information you provide to another third party as part of a sale of the assets of Jobzella Corporation, a subsidiary or division, or as the result of a change in control of the company. Any third party to which Jobzella transfers or sells Jobzella’s assets will have the right to continue to use the personal and other information that you provide to us.

A. Accessing and Changing Your Account Information:

You can review the personal information you provided to us and make any desired changes to the information you publish, or to the settings for your Jobzella account including your email and contact preferences, at any time by logging in to your account on the Jobzella website. Please be aware that even after your request for a change is processed, Jobzella may, for a time, retain residual information about you in its backup and/or archival copies of its database.

B. Default Settings:

Because the mission of Jobzella is to connect the world’s professionals to enable them to become more productive and successful, we have established what we believe to be reasonable default settings that we have found most professionals desire. Because Users may use and interact with Jobzella in a variety of ways, and because those uses may change over time, we designed our settings to provide our users granular control over the information they share. We encourage our Users to review their account settings and adjust them in accordance with their preferences.

C. De-activating Your Account:

You can de-activate your account through the Jobzella customer service. If you close your Jobzella account, we will remove your name and other personally identifiable information from our publicly viewable database. If you close your account, we have no obligation to retain your information, and may delete any or all of your account information without liability. However, we may retain certain data contributed by you if Jobzella believes it may be necessary to prevent fraud or future abuse, or for legitimate business purposes, such as analysis of aggregated, non-personally identifiable data, account recovery, or if required by law. Jobzella may also retain and use your information if necessary to provide the Services to other Users. For example, just as an email you may send to another person through an email service provider resides in that person’s inbox even after you delete it from your sent files or close your account, emails or direct messages you send on Jobzella to other Users, as well as your contributions to Jobzella Answers or Groups, may remain visible to others after you have closed your account. Similarly, other information you have shared with others, or that other Users have copied, may also remain visible. Jobzella disclaims any liability in relation to the deletion or retention (subject to the terms herein) of information or any obligation not to delete the information. Jobzella does not control when search engines update their cache, which may contain certain public profile information that has since been removed from Jobzella’s publicly viewable database.

D. Memorializing Accounts:

If we learn that a User is deceased, we may memorialize the User’s account. In these cases we may restrict profile access, remove messaging functionality, and close an account if we receive a formal request from the User’s next of kin or other proper legal request to do so.

As a User, you have certain obligations to other Users. Some of these obligations are imposed by applicable law and regulations, and others have become commonplace in user-friendly communities of like-minded members such as Jobzella:

  * You must, at all times, abide by the terms and conditions of the then-current Privacy Policy and Terms of Use Agreement. This includes respecting all intellectual property rights that may belong to third parties (such as trademarks or photographs).
  * You must not download or otherwise disseminate any information that may be deemed to be injurious, violent, offensive, racist or xenophobic, or which may otherwise violate the purpose and spirit of Jobzella and its community of Users.
  * You must not provide to Jobzella and/or other Users information that you believe might be injurious or detrimental to your person or to your professional or social status.
  * You must keep your username and password confidential and not share it with others.

Any violation of these guidelines may lead to the restriction, suspension or termination of your account at the sole discretion of Jobzella.

Children and Minors

Children under the age of 18 are not eligible to use our service.

A. Changes to this Privacy Policy:

We may update this Privacy Policy at any time, with or without advance notice. In the event there are significant changes in the way we treat your personally identifiable information, or in the Privacy Policy document itself, we will display a notice on the Jobzella website or send you an email, so that you may review the changed terms prior to continuing to use the site. As always, if you object to any of the changes to our terms, and you no longer wish to use Jobzella, you may deactivate. Unless stated otherwise, our current Privacy Policy applies to all information that Jobzella has about you and your account.

Using the Jobzella Services after a notice of changes has been sent to you or published on our site shall constitute consent to the changed terms or practices.

This policy covers how we use your personal information. We take your privacy seriously and will take all measures to protect your personal information. Any personal information received will only be used to fill your order. We will not sell or redistribute your information to anyone. 

In order to help secure your personal information, access to your data on Jobzella is password-protected, and sensitive data is protected by SSL encryption when it is exchanged between your web browser and the Jobzella website. To protect any data you store on our servers, Jobzella also regularly audits its system for possible vulnerabilities and attacks, and we use a tier-one secured-access data center. However, since the internet is not a 100% secure environment, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to Jobzella. There is no guarantee that information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards. It is your responsibility to protect the security of your login information. Please note that emails, instant messaging, and similar means of communication with other Users of Jobzella are not encrypted, and we strongly advise you not to communicate any confidential information through these means.

If you have questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, please contact us on customer.service@jobzella.com.
